Kaylee Swenson

MU Profile • Website • kscf5@umsystem.edu • (316) 253-5339

Summary

Political science Ph.D. candidate studying NASA and the American space industry, public opinion, American bureaucracy, and qualitative methods. Experienced in analyzing, summarizing, and presenting complex information to a wide audience, in addition to data management. Leadership roles have lead to exemplary communication skills and significant experience in planning and executing social and educational events.

Education

| PhD, Political Science, University of Missouri | Expected May 2024 |
|--|-------------------|
| MA, American Studies, Northeastern State University, Oklahoma | August 2018 |
| BA, magna cum laude, Visual Communication, Northeastern State University, Oklahoma | May 2016 |

Work Experience

University of Missouri

Columbia, Missouri

o Teaching Assistant/Graduate Instructor Fall 2019 - Spring 2023

Assistant to the professor for undergraduate-level courses, handling communication with students, grading, and administrative tasks such as fielding exams. For one semester served as the instructor of record.

O Research Assistant

Assistant to professors regarding their research, with tasks including data

Collection and management, summarizing previous research, and book indexing.

Summer 2020

Summer 2019

o Archival Research September 2020

Locating/replicating original documents found in the archives of the State Historical Society of Missouri for Dr. Rod Kiewiet (CalTech)

Zoe Institute

Tahlequah, Oklahoma Summer 2018

o Day Center Intern

Intern at the Day Center, a center for community members experiencing homelessness to receive aid and services. Intern tasks were primarily data management, in addition to assisting with meals and cleaning.

Northeastern State University

Tahlequah, Oklahoma Fall 2014-Summer 2018

o University Housing Resident Assistant/Student Hall Director

Responded to emergencies, handled administrative tasks, and planned community programs for the residence halls. Initially responsible for a single floor of residents as a Resident Assistant, then as Student Hall Director led a team of Resident Assistants with responsibilities for an entire residence hall building.

Service

| Coordinating Assistant, APSA Peer-to-Peer Pedagogical Conference, Columbia, MO | August 2022 |
|---|-------------|
| President, Graduate Association of Political Scientists, University of Missouri | 2021-2022 |
| Secretary, Graduate Association of Political Scientists, University of Missouri | 2020-2021 |

Awards & Certificates

| o Graduate Assistantship, Truman School of Government and Public Affairs | 2019-Present |
|---|--------------|
| o Gus T. Ridgel Fellowship, <i>University of Missouri</i> | 2019-Present |
| o Outstanding Student Academic Achievement Award, Northeastern State University | 2018 |
| o Introductory Leadership Certificate, Northeastern State University | 2017 |

Kaylee Swenson

<u>MU Profile</u> • <u>Website</u> • <u>kscf5@umsystem.edu</u> • (316) 253-5339

References

| Name | Employer | Title | Email |
|--------------------|------------------------|--|-----------------------|
| Dr. James Endersby | University of Missouri | Professor | Endersby@missouri.edu |
| Dr. Lael Keiser | University of Missouri | Director of Truman School of Government and Public Affairs | Keiserl@missouri.edu |
| Dr. Linda Godwin | University of Missouri | Professor Emeritus | Godwinl@missouri.edu |